<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funding on RSSLab @ Pitt</title>
    <link>https://rsslab.io/funding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funding on RSSLab @ Pitt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rsslab.io/funding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>University of Pittsburgh Cyber Energy Center</title>
      <link>https://rsslab.io/funding/doe_cyber_energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rsslab.io/funding/doe_cyber_energy/</guid>
      <description>The Cyber Energy Center is dedicated to developing cybersecurity solutions and addressing the needs of the evolving cyber-energy workforce. The RSSLab&amp;rsquo;s research in the center focuses on using digital twins to support intrusion tolerance in power grid systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Linux-Based Intrusion-Tolerant Networks</title>
      <link>https://rsslab.io/funding/dla_overlays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rsslab.io/funding/dla_overlays/</guid>
      <description>This project investigates how to enable legacy applications to use intrusion-tolerant overlay networks. This enables resilient communication for such applications (ensuring messages are delivered in a timely manner, even when the network is under attack), without requiring any changes to the application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Severe Impact Resilience: Assessment Framework for Adaptive Compound Threats</title>
      <link>https://rsslab.io/funding/serdp_severe_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rsslab.io/funding/serdp_severe_impact/</guid>
      <description>This project investigates how to model critical infrastructure resilience to compound threats involving natural disasters and opportunistic cyberattacks, and how to design new system architectures to better withstand these threats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enriching Citizen-Science data using context, feedback and community-oriented communication</title>
      <link>https://rsslab.io/funding/yods_data_storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rsslab.io/funding/yods_data_storytelling/</guid>
      <description>This project investigates how data storytelling workshops can be used to support local residents&amp;rsquo; understanding of air quality data and how it can be used to advocate for change.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
